<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ML Odyssey</title><description>Blog about machine learning, statistics and other Computer Science related stuff. I write about things I've learned while taking online courses.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 20:39:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>On supervised and unsupervised learning. Gradient descent demystified.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/on-supervised-and-unsupervised-learning-gradient-descent-demystified/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a35f24-5691-4a3d-966c-f911f0394149</guid><dc:creator>Jacek Kubiak</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 19:59:26 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Getting started</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Since you've already made your way here, there is a good chance you are one of those who find artificial intelligence fascinating. I do too, hence the blog. For quite some time now, I've been closely following the news and reading up on this topic. There is no doubt that&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/getting-started/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">30c44566-fb14-4abb-ad30-7f8fd5b07b24</guid><dc:creator>Jacek Kubiak</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 16:27:21 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/03/machina.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/03/machina.png" alt="Getting started"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since you've already made your way here, there is a good chance you are one of those who find artificial intelligence fascinating. I do too, hence the blog. For quite some time now, I've been closely following the news and reading up on this topic. There is no doubt that we are witnessing a giant progress in AI and before we realise, computers will &lt;del&gt;take over the world&lt;/del&gt; fill in the job positions that require people to perform mundane tasks and assist us in our day to day activities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to blog about how the world is going to change but instead you will here find my notes in a form of blogposts. What notes? Ah, right I forgot to tell you! I've recently enrolled to machine learning class on &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org"&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;, plus I started working through the &lt;a href="https://www.openintro.org/stat/"&gt;Open Intro Statistics textbook&lt;/a&gt;. The notes will contain the material from the sources above. Hopefully, writing them will help me get familiar with the new terms and the readers will find them worthy as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This machine learning thing... I did hear this term somewhere, but do you mind telling me what's all the fuss about? Sure thing! Machine learning is the field of study that gives computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed. It allows us to model and develop software which otherwise would be nearly impossible to create because of the endless amount of conditions and factors that change the program's behaviour. Think of a 'simple program' that given an image would tell you whether it shows a bird or a park &lt;a href="http://xkcd.com/1425/"&gt;obligatory xkcd comic&lt;/a&gt;. Flickr actually created this app and you can check it &lt;a href="http://parkorbird.flickr.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. All they had to do was feed the algorithm some training data explicitly labeled as a park or a bird and the program took over from there. This was an example of a supervised learning. Supervised and unsupervised learning are the two main types of ML algorithms. I'm going to talk more about them in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bird-or-park program is cool but it's use case is rather limited. Is machine learning a real thing? Why would we be convinced that it's going to have a meaningful impact on us in the near future? Oh well, for a number of reasons actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="chessandgocomputersdontstandachanceordothey"&gt;Chess and go? Computers don't stand a chance... or do they?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/03/chess.png" alt="Getting started"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For quite some time, people were assured that computers will never achieve the same level of intelligence as humans. In order to measure computer mental abilities, we had them play board games, such as chess or go, versus humans. Because these games have a large problem space, that is a total number of possible moves (10&lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;, 10&lt;sup&gt;170&lt;/sup&gt; for chess and go respectively) it is impossible for a computer to use the brute force method and come up with a solution in a feasible amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For chess, this thinking turned out to be wrong. The IBM's Deep Blue was a chess playing computer, capable of evaluating 200 million positions per second. In May 1997 Deep Blue defeated Garry Kasparov, who at that time was a world champion. The result was 4-2 in favour of Deep Blue and despite &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/2012/09/deep-blue-computer-bug/"&gt;controversies&lt;/a&gt; the computer was declared the winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to go, the same approach is not going to work for many upcoming years even though the computing power is rising exponentially. Go is simply much more complex than chess. This didn't discourage the Google's Deep Mind team who created Alpha Go. AlphaGo's algorithm uses a Monte Carlo tree search to find its moves based on knowledge previously "learned" by machine learning, specifically by an artificial neural network (a deep learning kind) by extensive training, both from human and computer play. We could say that through that training, AlphaGo obtained a form of human intuition which allows it to sort of "see" the areas on the board where the best moves could take place. This was a massive improvement from the brute force method used by Deep Blue. In March 2016 we witnessed history being made as Alpha Go defeated 4-1 Lee Sidol, South Korean professional considered as one of the greatest Go players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alpha Go's victory was something more than another proof that machine always eventually becomes better than a human at performing particular task. It proved that the deep learning method which uses neural networks, modelled after the brain’s neurons is a viable method, even though that in the 1980s it was dismissed as bunk by the AI establishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="fromsmalltobigdata"&gt;From small to big data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/03/memor.png" alt="Getting started"&gt;
The Apollo Guidance Computer used in the Apollo 11 mission  (&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/projectapolloarchive/albums"&gt;btw I totally recommend checking the photographs taken by the crew during the expedition&lt;/a&gt;) had 74 kilobytes of memory. This is several orders of magnitude less than what we have in ... our personal computers. External storage devices have more capacity as well and even if you run out of space there are still cloud services offering you pretty much an unlimited space. As a result, we are not only storing but also generating more data than never before. It's hard to comprehend but it turns out we have produced more pieces of information in the last two years than ever since we gathered the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine learning won't work if we don't provide solid training examples. More data naturally means more capabilities. With the rise of wearables, we've started tracking our heart rate, blood pressure, sleep patterns and nowadays we are able to quickly discover that a certain person has e.g. heart arrhythmia. All this person has to do is wear a watch long enough to produce relevant pieces of information and the ML algorithm built into the watch is able to detect any potential symptoms based on thousands of other training examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="machinelearningisgoingmainstream"&gt;Machine learning is going mainstream&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example given above is just a tip of the iceberg. Machine learning, even though rather unnoticeable by the less tech savvy people, is everywhere. Thanks to spam filters we are no longer concerned with ads and malicious emails. Think of all the recommendations we get while watching youtube videos, listening to music on spotify or shopping on amazon. Google search is personalised based on your browser history. Both speech and image recognition have greatly improved over the past few years. We now have a personal assistants like Siri - that's a great use of natural language processing. Who knew? All these examples have something in common and suprise suprise... it's machine learning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, that's quite a list. We can be certain that it will only keep growing, as we produce more and more data allowing us to apply ML algorithms to new areas. Looks like there is no coming back ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="excitingnews"&gt;Exciting news&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said at the beginning, for the next few months I will be posting notes about topics related to machine learning and statistics. If you found yourself curious feel more than free to stop by from time to time as I publish new content. In the meantime check out the curated list of resources I've prepared for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@ageitgey/machine-learning-is-fun-80ea3ec3c471"&gt;https://medium.com/@ageitgey/machine-learning-is-fun-80ea3ec3c471&lt;/a&gt; - good and short introduction to machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/10/future-of-artificial-intelligence/"&gt;http://www.wired.com/2014/10/future-of-artificial-intelligence/&lt;/a&gt; - an articles discussing the key factors that contributed to ML's recent growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.innoarchitech.com/machine-learning-an-in-depth-non-technical-guide/"&gt;http://www.innoarchitech.com/machine-learning-an-in-depth-non-technical-guide/&lt;/a&gt; - long and not so easy (but rewarding!) series of posts that serve as a very thorough intro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MachineLearning/wiki/index"&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/MachineLearning/wiki/index&lt;/a&gt; - subreddit dedicated to... you guessed it - machine learning. There's a lot of interesting stuff there poping out every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and of course, if you'd also like to take a Coursera class you can find it &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>